Jaime Suarez

Data Analyst

+ 1 4376610311

iaimeandresuarez@gmail.com

https://jaimesuarezdata.github.io/

https://github.com/jase311

in www.linkedin.com/in/jaime-suarez-62bb27174

▼ Toronto, ON

Data analyst with a solid foundation of financial analysis, mostly in the oil and gas industry. My background in financial evaluation of investments opportunities provides me with an expertise to provide valuable and quantifiable insights, transferable to any industry. I am a creative thinker who likes to solve day-to-day problems.

Education

Master in Business Administration 2018

University of New Brunswick, Saint John, NB, Canada.

Applied Mathematics Diploma 2014

Universidad Sergio Arboleda, Colombia.

Bachelor in Finance 2016

Universidad Sergio Arboleda, Colombia.

Certifications

Data Analyst Certificate 2024

Career Foundry.

IBM Data Analyst Specialization 2022

Coursera.

Work Experience

Financial Analyst

Fleet Complete (Telematics). Toronto, ON. (Sep 2023 - Present):

- Data wrangling.
- Data cleaning.
- Data reconciliation.

Financial Analyst

Ecopetrol (Oil & Gas). Colombia. (Jul 2019 - Jun 2023):

- Financial analysis and modeling.
- Investment portfolio prioritization.
- Financial evaluation of projects.
- Presentation of financial results.

Financial Analyst

Ecopetrol - Outsourced (Oil & Gas). Colombia. (Feb 2019 - Jun 2019):

- Financial analysis and modeling.
- Financial modeling.
- Excel modeling.

Budget Analyst

OHL Concesiones (Construction). Colombia. (Jun 2016 - Jan 2017):

- Financial analysis and modeling.
- Budget control and variance analysis.
- Presentation of financial results.

Financial Analyst

Ecopetrol - Outsourced (Oil & Gas). Colombia. (Aug 2011 - Jun 2017):

- Financial analysis and modeling.
- · Financial modeling.
- Excel modeling.

Chief of Financial Planning and Risk

Leasing Bolivar (Finance industry). Colombia. (Apr 2009 - Aug 2011)

- Financial risks management.
- Portfolio valuation.
- · Company budget planning and analysis.
- Financial statements projections and analysis.
- Financial modeling to implement, measure or improve the financial impacts of the company's forecasts.

Tech Skills:













Skills:

- Data Analysis.
- o Financial Analysis.
- Project Finance.
- o Cash Flow Analysis.
- o Machine learning.
- Data visualization.

Soft Skills:

- o Critical thinking.
- o Problem solving.
- o Curious.
- o Attentive to detail.
- o Objective oriented.
- o Teamwork.
- o Time management.
- o Innovative.

Languages:

- o English.
- o Spanish.

Projects on my website:

Energy Outlook: This project analyzes fossil, nuclear and renewable energy production and their impact on carbon dioxide emissions. Through data analysis it seeks to uncover patterns, disparities and potential mitigation strategies.

Tools: Python and Excel for data cleaning and wrangling. Tableau for visualization.

Medical Staffing: This project analyzes how influenza affects different age groups in the US and identifies states with higher infection rates. By pinpointing theses areas, it guides the allocation of medical staff during flu season.

Tools: Python and Excel for data cleaning and wrangling. Tableau for visualization.

Renewable Energy Outlook: This dashboard analyzes renewable energy sources in the top ten countries. It offers insights into each country's renewable energy landscape, thus allowing users to explore trends, compare contributions from different sources, and assess the progress towards renewable energy goals across these nations.

Tools: Python and Excel for data cleaning and wrangling. Python and Streamlit for visualization.